<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept audience="GSAR"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            id="GSAM_552_215_70">
		    <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="GSAR">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">552.215-70</ph> Examination of Records by GSA.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
			      <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph "> 
               <xref class="- topic/xref "
                     href="515.209-70.dita#GSAM_515_209_70"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">515.209-70</xref> 
            </ph>(a)
insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">Examination of Records
by GSA (Jun 2016)</p>
			      <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">The Contractor agrees that the Administrator
of General Services or any duly authorized representatives shall,
until the expiration of 3 years after final payment under this contract,
or of the time periods for the particular records specified in Subpart
4.7 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (48 CFR 4.7), whichever
expires earlier, have access to and the right to examine any books, documents,
papers, and records of the Contractor involving transactions related
to this contract or compliance with any clauses thereunder. The
Contractor further agrees to include in all its subcontracts hereunder
a provision to the effect that the subcontractor agrees that the
Administrator of General Services or any authorized representatives
shall, until the expiration of 3 years after final payment under
the subcontract, or of the time periods for the particular records
specified in Subpart 4.7 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (48
CFR 4.7), whichever expires earlier, have access to and the right
to examine any books, documents, papers, and records of such subcontractor
involving transactions related to the subcontract or compliance
with any clauses thereunder. The term “subcontract” as used in this
clause excludes (a) purchase orders not exceeding the simplified
acquisition threshold and (b) subcontracts or purchase orders for
public utility services at rates established for uniform applicability
to the general public.</p>
			      <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
