<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
	  <concept audience="GSAR" id="GSAM_552_238_117">
      <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="GSAR" rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">552.238-117</ph> Price Adjustment—Failure to Provide Accurate Information</title>
      <conbody>
         <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF"><xref href="538.273.dita#GSAM_538_273" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">538.273</xref>(d)</ph>(37), insert the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023">PRICE ADJUSTMENT—FAILURE TO PROVIDE ACCURATE INFORMATION (OCT 2023)</p>
         <ol>
            <li>
               <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>The Government, at its election, may reduce the price of this contract or contract modification if the Contracting Officer determines after award of this contract or contract modification that the price negotiated was increased by a significant amount because the Contractor failed to: </p>
               <ol>
                  <li>
                     <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>Provide information required by this solicitation/contract or otherwise requested by the Government; or </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>Submit information that was current, accurate, and complete; or </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>Disclose changes in the Contractor’s commercial pricelist(s), discounts or discounting policies which occurred after the original submission and prior to the completion of negotiations. </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>The Government will consider information submitted to be current, accurate and complete if the data is current, accurate and complete as of 14 calendar days prior to the date it is submitted. </p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>If any reduction in the contract price under this clause reduces the price for items for which payment was made prior to the date of the modification reflecting the price reduction, the Contractor shall be liable to and shall pay the United States— </p>
               <ol>
                  <li>
                     <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>The amount of the overpayment; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>Simple interest on the amount of such overpayment to be computed from the date(s) of overpayment to the Contractor to the date the Government is repaid by the Contractor at the applicable underpayment rate effective each quarter prescribed by the Secretary of Treasury under 26 U.S.C.6621(a)(2). </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>Failure to agree on the amount of the decrease shall be resolved as a dispute. </p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>In addition to the remedy in paragraph (a) of this clause, the Government may terminate this contract for default. The rights and remedies of the Government specified herein are not exclusive, and are in addition to any other rights and remedies provided by law or under this contract. </p>
               <p outputclass="Endofclause" rev="Change 171 October 12, 2023"> (End of clause)</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
