<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="id1945FG00762"
            audience="GSAR"
            otherprops="H4H3_xx"
            outputclass="H4H3_xx"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
      <title outputclass="H4H3xx" xtrf="Grey" class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">552.236-71</ph> Contractor
Responsibilities.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p otherprops="Body" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <xref href="GSAM-536.571.dita#id1941F0V035U"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">536.571</xref>,
insert the following clause:</p>
         <p otherprops="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Contractor Responsibilities
(Mar 2019)</p>
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  The
Contractor shall be responsible for compliance with applicable codes,
standards and regulations pertaining to the health and safety of
personnel during performance of the contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  Unless expressly
stated otherwise in the contract, the Contractor shall be responsible
for all means and methods employed in the performance of the contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  The Contractor
shall immediately bring to the Contracting Officer's attention any
hazardous materials or conditions not disclosed in the contract
documents discovered by or made known to the Contractor during the
performance of the contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  The Contractor
shall be responsible for providing professional design services
in connection with performance of the work or portions of the work
only if this responsibility is expressly stated in the contract,
and the contract documents provide the performance and design criteria
that such services will be required to satisfy. In the performance
of such work, the Contractor shall be responsible for retaining
licensed design professionals, who shall sign and seal all drawings,
calculations, specifications and other submittals that the licensed
professional prepares. The Contractor shall be responsible for,
and GSA shall be entitled to rely upon, the adequacy and completeness
of all professional design services provided under the contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  Where installation
of separate work components as shown in the contract will result
in conflict or interference between such components or with existing
conditions, including allowable tolerances, it is the Contractor's
responsibility to bring such conflict or interference to the attention
of the Contracting Officer and seek direction before fabrication,
construction, or installation of any affected work. If the Contractor
fabricates, constructs, or installs any work prior to receiving
such direction, the Contractor shall be responsible for all cost
and time incurred to resolve or mitigate such conflict or interference.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  Where drawings
show work without specific routing, dimensions, locations, or position
relative to other work or existing conditions, and such information
is not specifically defined by reference to specifications or other
information supplied in the contract, the Contractor is responsible
for routing, dimensioning, and locating such work in coordination
with other work or existing conditions in a manner consistent with
contract requirements.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  It is not
the Contractor's responsibility to ensure that the contract documents
comply with applicable laws, statutes, building codes and regulations.
If it comes to the attention of the Contractor that any of the contract
documents do not comply with such requirements, the Contractor shall
promptly notify the Contracting Officer in writing. If the Contractor performs
any of the work prior to notifying and receiving direction from
the Contracting Officer, the Contractor shall assume full responsibility
for correction of such work, and any fees or penalties that may
be assessed for non-compliance.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p otherprops="Body_Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of
clause)</p>
         <p otherprops="Body_Alternate_NoIndent" class="- topic/p ">Alternate
I (<term otherprops="SmallCaps" class="- topic/term ">Mar</term> 2019).
As prescribed in <xref href="GSAM-536.571.dita#id1941F0V035U"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">536.571</xref>,
delete paragraphs (d), (e), (f), and (g) of the basic clause, and
insert paragraphs (d), (e), (f), and (g) as follows:</p>
         <p otherprops="Body_Alternate_List1" class="- topic/p ">(d)
The Contractor shall be responsible for providing professional design
services unless this responsibility is expressly excluded from the
contract. In the performance of such work, the Contractor shall
be responsible for retaining licensed design professionals, who shall
sign and seal all drawings, calculations, specifications and other
submittals that the licensed professional prepares. The Contractor shall
be responsible for, and GSA shall be entitled to rely upon, the
adequacy and completeness of all professional design services provided under
the contract.</p>
         <p otherprops="Body_Alternate_List1" class="- topic/p ">(e)
The Contractor's responsibilities include the responsibilities of
the Architect-Engineer Contractor, as specified in FAR 52.236-23.</p>
         <p otherprops="Body_Alternate_List1" class="- topic/p ">(f)
The Contractor shall include in all subcontracts that require professional
design services express terms establishing GSA as a third party
beneficiary. No other person shall be deemed a third party beneficiary
of the contract.</p>
         <p otherprops="Body_Alternate_List1" class="- topic/p ">(g)
The Contractor shall determine whether the information contained
in the contract documents complies with applicable laws, statutes,
building codes and regulations. If it comes to the attention of
the Contractor that any of the contract documents do not comply
with such requirements, the Contractor shall promptly notify the
Contracting Officer in writing. If the Contractor performs any of
the work prior to notifying and receiving direction from the Contracting
Officer, the Contractor shall assume full responsibility for correction
of such work, and any fees or penalties that may be assessed for
non-compliance.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
