<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="i1875716">
      <title xtrc="GSAR">
         <ph props="autonumber">552.211-75</ph> Preservation, Packaging, and Packing.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p audience="GSAR" id="aKefnz">As prescribed in <xref href="GSAM-WCKQYVDR.dita#WCKQYVDR" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">511.204</xref>(b)(2), insert the following clause:</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" id="FvAUQE" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">Preservation, Packaging, and Packing (Feb 1996)</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" id="kkkIEe">Unless otherwise specified, all items shall be preserved, packaged, and packed in accordance with normal commercial practices, as defined in the applicable commodity specification. Packaging and packing shall comply with the requirements of the Uniform Freight Classification and the National Motor Freight Classification (issue in effect at time of shipment) and each shipping container of each item in a shipment shall be of uniform size and content, except for residual quantities. Where special or unusual packing is specified in an order, but not specifically provided for by the contract, such packing details must be the subject of an agreement independently arrived at between the ordering agency and the Contractor.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" id="uiVFXP" outputclass="Endofclause Ctr">(End of clause)</p>
         <section>
            
            <p audience="GSAR" id="yQkxWl">
               <i>Alternate I</i> (MAY
               2003)<i>.</i> As prescribed at <xref href="GSAM-WCKQYVDR.dita#WCKQYVDR" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">511.204</xref>(b)(2), substitute the following sentence for the last sentence of the basic clause:</p>
            <p audience="GSAR" id="EIOsIz">Where special or unusual packing is specified in an order, but not specifically provided for by the contract, such packing details must be the subject of an agreement independently arrived at between the ordering activity and the Contractor.</p>
            
         </section>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
