<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="MLBSRBFW"
            audience="GSAR"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title xtrc="GSAR" class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">570.102</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“ANSI/BOMA Office Area (ABOA)” means
the area “where a tenant normally houses personnel, and/or furniture,
for which a measurement is to be computed,” as stated by the American
National Standards Institute/Building Owners and ManagersAssociation(ANSI/BOMA)publication
Z65.1-1996.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Contract” means lease.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Contractor” means lessor.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Landlord” or “lessor” means any individual,
firm, partnership, trust, association, State or local government,
or other legal entity that leases real property to the Government.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Lease” or “leasehold interest in real property”
means a conveyance to the Government of the right of exclusive possession of
real property for a definite period of time by a landlord. It may
include operational services provided by the landlord.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Lease acquisition” means the acquiring by
lease of an interest in improved real property for use by the Government,
whether the space already exists or must be constructed.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Lease extension” means extension of the expiration
date of a lease to provide for continued occupancy on a short term
basis.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Lease renewal” (option) means the right, but
not the obligation of the Government to continue a lease upon specified
terms and conditions, including lease term and rent.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Lessee” or “tenant” means the United States
of America.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Operational services” means services that
support use of a leased property, such as heating, ventilation,
air conditioning, utilities, and custodial services.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Simplified lease acquisition procedures” mean
the procedures for awarding leases at or below the simplified lease
acquisition threshold.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Simplified lease acquisition threshold” means
the simplified acquisition threshold (see FAR 2.101), when applied
to the average annual amount of rent for the term of the lease,
including option periods and excluding the cost of services.</p>
         <p id="d933e51" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Small business” means a concern
including affiliates, which is organized for profit, is independently-owned
and operated, is not dominant in the field of leasing commercial
real estate, and that has annual average gross receipts for the
preceding three fiscal years which are less than the size standard
established by the Small Business Administration pursuant to 13
CFR 121. The size standards may be found at <xref href="https://www.sba.gov/content/small-business-size-standards"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">https://www.sba.gov/content/small-business-size-standards</xref>.
For most lease procurements, the NAICS code is 531190.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Solicitation for Offers (SFO)” means a request
for proposals.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Substantially as follows” or “substantially
the same as,” when used in prescribing a provision or clause, means
that the contracting officer may prepare and use a variation of
that provision or clause to accommodate requirements peculiar to
an individual acquisition. The variation must include the salient
features of the FARor GSAR provision or clause. It must also be
consistent with the intent, principle, and substance of the FARor
GSAR provision or clause and related coverage on the subject matter.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Succeeding lease” means a lease whose effective
date immediately follows the expiration date of an existing lease
for space in the same building.</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">“Superseding lease” means a lease that replaces
an existing lease, prior to the scheduled expiration of the existing
lease term.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
