<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1874759"
            audience="GSAR"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title xtrc="GSAR" class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">552.270-9</ph> Inspection—Right
of Entry.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <xref href="GSAM-i1855352.dita#i1855352"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">570.703</xref>,
insert the following clause:</p>
         <p audience="GSAR" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Inspection—Right
of Entry (Sep 1999)</p>
         <ol id="d903e22" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li audience="GSAR" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d895e26" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                    At
any time and from time to time after receipt of an offer (until
the same has been duly withdrawn or rejected), after acceptance
thereof and during the term, the agents, employees and contractors
of the Government may, upon reasonable prior notice to Offeror or
Lessor, enter upon the offered premises or the premises, and all
other areas of the building access to which is necessary to accomplish
the purposes of entry, to determine the potential or actual compliance
by the Offeror or Lessor with the requirements of the solicitation
or this lease, which purposes shall include, but not be limited
to:</p>
               <ol id="d903e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li audience="GSAR" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d895e36" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                          Inspecting,
sampling and analyzing suspected asbestos-containing materials and
air monitoring for asbestos fibers;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li audience="GSAR" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d895e45" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                          Inspecting the heating,
ventilation and air conditioning system, maintenance records, and
mechanical rooms for the offered premises or the premises;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li audience="GSAR" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d895e54" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                          Inspecting for any leaks,
spills, or other potentially hazardous conditions which may involve
tenant exposure to hazardous or toxic substances; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li audience="GSAR" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d895e63" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                          Inspecting for any current
or past hazardous waste operations, to ensure that appropriate mitigative
actions were taken to alleviate any environmentally unsound activities
in accordance with Federal, State and local law.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li audience="GSAR" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d895e74" audience="GSAR" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                    Nothing in this clause
shall be construed to create a Government duty to inspect for toxic
materials or to impose a higher standard of care on the Government
than on other lessees. The purpose of this clause is to promote
the ease with which the Government may inspect the building. Nothing
in this clause shall act to relieve the Lessor of any duty to inspect or
liability which might arise as a result of Lessor’s failure to inspect
for or correct a hazardous condition.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p audience="GSAR" outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of Clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
