<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="JJLVHDUF"
            otherprops="H30109"
            outputclass="H30109"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
		    <title outputclass="H301-09" class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">507.7001</ph> Policy.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d152e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li otherprops="abc" outputclass="H5_abc" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d150e17" outputclass="H5_abc" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						             Although GSA’s mission does not include the direct acquisition of weapon systems on behalf of the Department of Defense (DoD), GSA contracting activities may procure information technology supplies, services and systems in support of a weapon system, which is part of a national security system (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, components, services to install and maintain weapon systems, ancillary items and services) when responding to a bona-fide requirement received from a requiring agency or program office.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li otherprops="abc" outputclass="H5_abc" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d150e29" outputclass="H5_abc" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						             Contracting Officers shall ensure that all requiring agency regulations and the policies and directives of The Committee on National Security Systems at <xref href="http://www.cnss.gov"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">www.cnss.gov</xref> are incorporated during the acquisition planning stage and are met before acquiring information technology supplies, services and systems in support of a weapon system as part of a national security system.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li otherprops="abc" outputclass="H5_abc" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d150e42" outputclass="H5_abc" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						             Employees responsible for or procuring information technology supplies, services and systems in support of a weapon system shall possess the appropriate security clearance associated with the level of security classification related to the acquisition. They include, but are not limited to contracting officers, contract specialists, project/program managers, and contracting officer representatives.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
