<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="GSAM_504_1670"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">504.1670</ph> Unique identifier
for procurements supporting a leasehold interest.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General</i>.
Procurements supporting a leasehold interest include: architectural
and engineering (A&amp;E) design and other related activities, project
management, construction, space alterations (irrespective of size
or scope), security-related tenant buildout, building-specific security
countermeasures, personal (moveable) property, and overtime utilities.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Procurement Actions</i>.
Any procurement supporting a leasehold interest (including those
at or below the micro-purchase threshold), including stand-alone
contracts or lease amendments, must reference the associated lease
number (8-character number such as LMA00001) in the system of record
(e.g., EASi, G-REX, RETA, REXUS, Pegasys) in which that action is
being processed or recorded, and on the procurement document. Data
must be recorded in a standardized data field, as appropriate. For
systems that do not have the capability to capture the associated
lease number, the lease number may be placed on the procurement
document itself alone.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Reimbursable Work Authorizations
(RWAs)</i>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">RWAs prior to
lease award</i>. For any RWA submissions (including at or below
the micro-purchase threshold) where the lease is not yet awarded,
the associated lease number (8-character number such as LMA00001)
shall be input into the system of record for the RWA and on the
procurement document, within 3 business days of the lease award
date or the creation of a lease number, whichever is later. Data
must be recorded in a standardized data field, as appropriate. For
systems that do not have the capability to capture the associated
lease number, the lease number may be placed on the procurement
document itself alone.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">RWAs after lease award</i>.
For any RWA submissions (including at or below the micro-purchase
threshold) where the lease is already awarded, the associated lease
number (8-character number such as LMA00001) shall be input into the
system of record for the RWA and on the procurement document. Data
must be recorded in a standardized data field, as appropriate. For
systems that do not have the capability to capture the associated
lease number, the lease number may be placed on the procurement
document itself alone.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
