<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="GSAM_508_770" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">508.770</ph> AbilityOne Representative (ABOR) responsibilities.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">The Office of Federal Procurement Policy memorandum, Increasing the Participation of Americans with Disabilities in Federal Contracting, requires each Chief Financial Officers Act agency to designate an agency-level ABOR. Each Service (i.e., FAS and PBS) shall designate a Service-level ABOR.</p>
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Agency-level ABOR responsibilities</i>. Responsibilities of the Agency-level ABOR include, but not limited to—</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>Developing and maintaining an agency action plan for increasing the use of the AbilityOne Program and meeting with the SPE on a regular basis to discuss progress made against the action plan; </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>Conducting in-reach and training activities with the GSA acquisition workforce to bring greater attention to the AbilityOne Program; </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>Identifying contract performance mitigation measures; </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>Collaborating with the AbilityOne Commission, GSA Acquisition Innovation Advocates, GSA Industry Liaisons, and other stakeholders regarding acquisition strategies that promote increased participation of people with disabilities in the workforce through use of AbilityOne nonprofit agencies or other private sector contractors; </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>Consulting with the Office of Small Disadvantaged Business Utilization to coordinate actions that may simultaneously promote the achievement of small business goals and increase purchases from AbilityOne nonprofit agencies (e.g., use of distributors of AbilityOne products and subcontracting possibilities); and </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>In coordination with the SPE, establishing a pledge to award a percentage of the agency’s total contract spend on AbilityOne products and services each year. Monitoring progress towards the pledge and working with management and the workforce to adjust practices as necessary and appropriate to ensure the pledge is met.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Service-level ABORs responsibilities</i>. Responsibilities of Service-level ABORs include, but not limited to—</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>Supporting the Agency-level ABOR, as necessary, to increase the use of the AbilityOne Program across GSA (e.g., developing training and program utilization strategies; promoting program participation within their respective Service(s); and identifying potential opportunities that may be suitable for addition to the Procurement List);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>As applicable, participating in acquisition reviews (see <xref href="Subpart_504.71.dita#GSAM_Subpart_504_71"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  504.71</xref>); and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>Assisting the acquisition workforce on the use of the AbilityOne Program (e.g., acquisition planning (see <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              href="507.104.dita#GSAM_507_104"
                              base="gsam-507.104"
                              xtrc="507.104"
                              class="- topic/xref "/>), market research, subcontracting considerations, and inclusion of FAR clause <xref scope="external"
                              format="html"
                              href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/52.208-9"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.208-9</xref>).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
