<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="GSAM_536_602_1" audience="GSAM">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">536.602-1</ph> Selection criteria.</title>
      <conbody>
         <ol id="d642e13">
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e17">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <xref href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/36.602-1"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external">FAR 36.602-1</xref> requires that agencies include “location in the general geographical area of the project and knowledge of locality of the project” as one of several selection criteria.</p>
               <ol id="d642e23">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e27">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                          Do not use this evaluation
factor as a minimum qualification requirement for determining whether
a firm is eligible to compete for a proposed project.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>   This factor must not exceed 5 percent of the total weight of all evaluation criteria. In order to receive the maximum score for this factor, the architect-engineer firm(s) must demonstrate that at least 35 percent of the architect-engineer contract services (based on the total contract price) will be accomplished within the geographical boundaries established for the project.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e45">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> 
                        FAR Deviation. Under an approved class deviation from <xref href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/36.602-1"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external">FAR 36.602-1</xref>(a)(5), this factor does not apply to projects that the Chief Architect of GSA determines have national significance.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d660e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> 
                        For procurements that are not project specific, such as indefinite-delivery indefinite-quantity contracts, evaluate based on the geographical area(s) covered by the contract.
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e56">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>  The public announcement for a proposed project should identify the general geographical area of the project such as:
               </p>
               <ol id="d642e62">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e66">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>  A radius in miles or other appropriate unit of measure, or
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e75">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>  The Metropolitan Statistical Area, county(ies), or state(s) surrounding the project.
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d636e86">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>  For more information on the Architect Engineer selection process, see the GSA Design Excellence Policies and Procedures at <xref href="http://gsa.gov/designexcellence"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"/>.
               </p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
